<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Christian Saal</title>
    <link>https://christian43.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Christian Saal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 09:18:30 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://christian43.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DFB Nachwuchsleistungszentren</title>
      <link>https://christian43.github.io/project/nlz_map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christian43.github.io/project/nlz_map/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Map of Potsdam</title>
      <link>https://christian43.github.io/project/potsdam_map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christian43.github.io/project/potsdam_map/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter ECSS Wordcloud</title>
      <link>https://christian43.github.io/project/wordcloud_tweets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christian43.github.io/project/wordcloud_tweets/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serial documents with LaTeX</title>
      <link>https://christian43.github.io/post/2021-07-09-serialletter/2021-07-09-serialletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 09:18:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christian43.github.io/post/2021-07-09-serialletter/2021-07-09-serialletter/</guid>
      <description>Serial Documents Often i have a task were i have to send documents or letters with an equal layout but different informations on it. The most prominient task surely are serial letters. To solve this task i use either MS Word or preferably LaTeX. The latter impresses with its excellent typesetting system.
What you need  data source LaTeX template  The data source often comes as a plain formatted csv file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpretation of statistical models by using DALEX</title>
      <link>https://christian43.github.io/post/2021-05-26-fifamlr3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christian43.github.io/post/2021-05-26-fifamlr3/</guid>
      <description>Intro In this post i follow a description on how to use the DALEX package that can help on model interpretation. The full example can be found in the MLR3 book here.
The authors used the FIFA20 dataset to train a random forest model that predicts the soccer player worth. Subsequently they show how to use DALEX to analyze the model behaviour on a global level and of a single prediction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cluster Strings</title>
      <link>https://christian43.github.io/post/2021-05-07-levenshtein/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christian43.github.io/post/2021-05-07-levenshtein/</guid>
      <description>Distance between strings  Edit distance, also called Levensthein distance, is a measure of the number of primary edits that would need to be made to transform one string into another. &amp;ndash; Jack Davies Here is a small example where the function adist() from the R Utils package that is part of the R Distribution.
 we create a vector containing six words next we calculate the edit distance then using a hierachical cluster analysis to find similarities  s_vec &amp;lt;- c(&amp;#34;alcool&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;alcohol&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;alcoholic&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;brandy&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;brandie&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;cachaça&amp;#34;) dist &amp;lt;- adist(s_vec) hc &amp;lt;- hclust(as.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datenschutz</title>
      <link>https://christian43.github.io/datenschutz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 19:53:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christian43.github.io/datenschutz/</guid>
      <description>Hosting Mein Hoster erhebt in sog. Logfiles folgende Daten, die Ihr Browser übermittelt:
IP-Adresse, die Adresse der vorher besuchten Website (Referer Anfrage-Header), Datum und Uhrzeit der Anfrage, Zeitzonendifferenz zur Greenwich Mean Time, Inhalt der Anforderung, HTTP-Statuscode, übertragene Datenmenge, Website, von der die Anforderung kommt und Informationen zu Browser und Betriebssystem.
Das ist erforderlich, um unsere Website anzuzeigen und die Stabilität und Sicherheit zu gewährleisten. Dies entspricht unserem berechtigten Interesse im Sinne des Art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressum</title>
      <link>https://christian43.github.io/impressum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 19:47:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christian43.github.io/impressum/</guid>
      <description>Angaben gemäß § 5 TMG
Christian Saal
Karl-Liebknecht-Straße 121
14482 Potsdam</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change Point Detection</title>
      <link>https://christian43.github.io/post/2021-04-26-changepoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christian43.github.io/post/2021-04-26-changepoint/</guid>
      <description>Könnte interessant sein.. In diesem Beitrag zeige ich ganz kurz und knapp wie Segmente innerhalb einer Verlaufskurve detektiert werden können. Verlaufskurven kommen im Sport ja recht häufig vor. Am Beispiel meiner Laufdaten, die von einer Smart Watch aufgezeichnet wurden, zeige ich eine mögliche Vorgehensweise mit R.
Eine schöne Übersicht über die verschiedenen Vorgehensweisen bietet Saskia Otto auf ihrer Homepage. Etwas ausführlicher beschäftigen sich Burg &amp;amp; Williams (2020) mit den verschiedenen Ansätzen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christian Saal</title>
      <link>https://christian43.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 21:26:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christian43.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>No one knows with certainty if it will rain tomorrow, but my decision to carry an umbrella will differ depending on the probability.
&amp;ndash; Andrew Ng After studying sport science in Berlin and finishing my Ph.D. at the University Leipzig i landed in Potsdam (Germany) and work as a freelancer in full time. Get a short CV.
I am interested in analysing data from different sources and delivering data-driven decision support.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
